

My Github | My LinkedIn | My Blog xiaowen0423@gmail.com | 647.868.5409

EDUCATION

RYERSON UNIVERSITY

CERTIFICATE IN

DATA ANALYTICS, BIG DATA, AND PREDICTIVE ANALYTICS Jan 2017 Toronto, Canada

THE CHINESE UNIVERSITY OF HONG KONG

PHD IN PSYCHOLOGY Grad. Dec 2011 | Hong Kong

PEKING UNIVERSITY

BS IN PSYCHOLOGY

Grad. June 2007 | Beijing, China

COURSEWORK

RYERSON UNIVERSITY

Data Analytics: Basic Methods Introduction to Big Data Data Organization for Data Analysts Data Analytics: Advanced Methods Big Data Analytics Tools

COURSERA

Machine Learning by Stanford University

DATAQUEST

Exploratory Data Visualization
Data Cleaning
SQL and Database
Natural Language Processing
Probability and Statistics in Python
Machine Learning in Python
Data Structures and Algorithms

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

Python • R • SAS/SPSS • Matlab • HTML/CSS • SQL • Shell • BASH

DATA TOOLS

Tableau • Scikit-learn • Matplotlib • Numpy • Pandas • XML

ANALYTICAL TECHNIQUES

Cluster • Regression • Multivariate • Segmentation • Machine Learning • Time Series • Sentiment • NLP

SUMMARY

Creative market analyst with applied statistical/data science experience. 3 years of experience in coordinating marketing strategies for luxuray retail business. 2 years of programming experience using SPSS, R, Python. Graduate level of training in multivariate statistical techniques. Enthusiasted in contributing business growth and acquiring new analytical techniques and software.

PROJECTS

(click to view)

- Predict insurance renewal and develop an incentive plan maximizing net revenue
- Tag webpage based on url and html content
- Data manipulation and Exploratory Analysis with NYC high school data
- NYPD Motor Vehicle Collisions: Data visualization using Tableau
- Data Behind Bank Telemarketing: Predict customer response to bank direct marketing using Decision Tree, Naive Bayes, Random Forest; Identify key features of customers who are most likely to subsequently subscribe to term deposits using cluster analysis: Provide business insights and strategies based on the results

EXPERIENCE

TOM LEE MUSIC | Marketing Coordinator

Dec 2014 - Aug 2017 | Toronto, ON

- Analyzed factors that contributed store traffic and planned store promotions and events to increase traffic and customer contact database
- Planned and implanted promotional campaigns and offsite events, e.g.,
 Canadian International AutoShow, Markham Music Festival, gala dinner
- Updated company website event page using html and increased traffic by 50%
- Managed and improved lead generation campaigns (online and offline activites) and measured lead effectiveness and quality
- Built a relational database using Access for a contest

UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO | PostDoc Researcher

Jan 2012 - Dec 2013 | Toronto, ON

- Used Eye-tracking technology to study how human scan faces during face recognition
- Conducted multivariate statistical analyses using SPSS, R, and Matlab
- Collaborated with team members to identify research objective and present findings in international conferences and workshops

THE CHINESE UNIVERSITY OF HONG KONG

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Sep 2007 - Aug 2011 | Hong Kong

- Taught undergraduate courses and led tutorial on applied statistics in psychology and basic learning processes
- Consistently received student evaluation in the 90th percentile